Omkar Savalkar

Front End Developer

Computer Software Engineer having strong work experience of 1.8 years as Front end developer with proven quick learning, best performing and team player ability. Have understanding of SDLC and Agile process with knowledge of working on web application development projects from scratch using frontend skills and seeking for more opportunitites in a reputed firm.

Website:- https://omkar-ownwebapp.vercel.app

EXPERIENCE

Xoriant Solutions Pvt. Ltd (Product-Service), Pune, Maharashtra **Software Engineer**

August 2021 - Present

- Contributed and developed client project's UI code from scratch using React (react hooks), Typescript and Material UI.
- Converted Figma to frontend UI with all its functionalities.
- Responsible for integrating 40% Rest API's involved with the front end.
- Worked on debugging, code bug fixes and resolving code issues.
- Implemented enhancements at later stages and demonstrated 5 successful workflow demos to clients.
- Attended client meetings, tested application, took complete responsibility by quickly delivering requirements along with continuous learning.

INTERNSHIP

HealByUs Healthcare, Pune, Maharashtra **Android Developer Intern**

June 2020 - Aug 2020

 Worked on a complete project and actively contributed in planning, UI design, development and testing with the team.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Connect Well (dynamic web application), Hackathon Project *Fullstack Developer*

November 2022 - January 2022

- Contributed in complete SDLC and majorly on coding of web application that can be integrated with company's portal.
- Tech Stack React Js, TypeScript, MUI, Next Js, Node Js, MongoDB

Portfolio (React web application), Remote

- Developed eye catching user friendly interface covering all required features for displaying my complete details.
- <u>Tech Stack</u> React Js, JavaScript, SASS, Styled-Components.

Address:- Pune, Maharashtra,

India. 411062

Mobile No:- +91-9766112890

Email:-

omkarsavalkar22@gmail.com

Linkedin:-

https://www.linkedin.com/in/

omkar-savalkar

Github profile:-

https://github.com/OmkarSav

alkar

SKILLS

React

Javascript & ES6+

Typescript

Material UI

Redux

Next Js

Node Js

HTML - CSS

SASS

Git

EDUCATION

Nutan Maharashtra Institute of Engineering and Technology | Pune University

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

June 2021

Pune, Maharashtra, India

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Achieved Xoriant Spot Award for Best Performance in team (Xoriant Solutions).
- 1st prize for Final Year
 Project in (UGCON) 2021